<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Russia on Privalko Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/russia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Russia on Privalko Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/russia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Job mobility with promotions</title>
      <link>/2019/05/05/job-mobility-with-promotions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/05/job-mobility-with-promotions/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been thinking a lot about capturing internal and external mobility types in the RLMS. I previously wrote a small note on one measure in the RLMS. That particular post was kind of disappointing, the data suggested that mobility was extremely uncommon, and although Russia is a famously immobile labour market, where respondents stay in the same job even when employers decide to stop paying wages, it seems like this question may be skewed somehow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Opinion of Ukraine and Ukrainian Opinion of Russia</title>
      <link>/2018/11/26/collective-opinion-in-russia-and-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/26/collective-opinion-in-russia-and-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>Levada recently updated statistics on what Russian and Ukrainian citizens think of each other. I saw the update but forgot to dig into the numbers; yesterday’s events in Kerch reminded me to revisit these.
It seems like conflict between both countries is on the rise, but it’s worth looking back on how public opinion changed over the quieter months. In this post I merge the data gathered by Levada, and use some dplyr commands to simplify things, I then make a graph using ggplot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compensating Differentials and Premiums for &#34;Dangerous Work&#34;</title>
      <link>/2018/02/04/compensating-differentials-and-premiums-for-dangerous-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/04/compensating-differentials-and-premiums-for-dangerous-work/</guid>
      <description>A key theory predicting differences in pay, and explaining pay inequality, lies in compensating differentials. This is the idea that pay premiums are attached to jobs that have unfavourable or dangerous working conditions. Thus, workers who are at risk earn more than equally skilled workers in safer jobs. The theory often gets cited by critics of the gender pay gap. Here, it is argued that women accept lower pay in trying to “buy” better working conditions (or simply more favourable conditions).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>