<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sociology on Privalko Blog</title>
    <link>/categories/sociology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sociology on Privalko Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/sociology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Opinion of Ukraine and Ukrainian Opinion of Russia</title>
      <link>/2018/11/26/collective-opinion-in-russia-and-ukraine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/26/collective-opinion-in-russia-and-ukraine/</guid>
      <description>Levada recently updated statistics on what Russian and Ukrainian citizens think of each other. I saw the update but forgot to dig into the numbers; yesterday’s events in Kerch reminded me to revisit these.
It seems like conflict between both countries is on the rise, but it’s worth looking back on how public opinion changed over the quieter months. In this post I merge the data gathered by Levada, and use some dplyr commands to simplify things, I then make a graph using ggplot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Thoughts on Politics and Government</title>
      <link>/2018/01/28/public-thoughts-on-politics-and-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/28/public-thoughts-on-politics-and-government/</guid>
      <description>The European Social Survey for 2016 lists variables on government and politics. These are worth exploring, especially with the rise of protests and public meetings against the Kremlin. Often, critics claim these are disingenuous movements, made to create media content in Europe and the States. Typically, they point to Putin’s high approval rating as a symbol that all is well, and the population holds pro-government views.
In this post I explore some specifics, how do Russians feel about government, their ability to impact policy, and their ability to influence political outcomes?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>