<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on tupac lives in moscow</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on tupac lives in moscow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Thoughts on Politics and Government</title>
      <link>/2018/01/28/public-thoughts-on-politics-and-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/28/public-thoughts-on-politics-and-government/</guid>
      <description>The European Social Survey for 2016 lists variables on government and politics. These are worth exploring, especially with the rise of protests and public meetings against the Kremlin. Often, critics claim these are disingenuous movements, made to create media content in Europe and the States. Typically, they point to Putin’s high approval rating as a symbol that all is well, and the population holds pro-government views.
In this post I explore some specifics, how do Russians feel about government, their ability to impact policy, and their ability to influence political outcomes?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Industry Differences in Pay</title>
      <link>/2017/12/30/gender-parental/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/30/gender-parental/</guid>
      <description>In this post I outline industry differences in pay, with a special focus on gender. I already listed the occupational differences in a previous post. Here, I follow the same idea, but substitute industry for occupations.
As before, I use the Russian Longitudinal Monitoring Survey for data on participants in 2015. I use a measure for gender, industry, the number of weekly hours worked, and gross wages.
I do not limit the industry codes, but focus on industry as it appears in the survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gender, occupations, and pay</title>
      <link>/2017/12/20/gender-occupations-and-pay/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/20/gender-occupations-and-pay/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I look at a small chart breaking down pay by gender and occupation. Russian wages are particularly flexible, employers have significant freedom in setting the earnings of “inefficient” workers. There’s also a lot of “hidden unemployment”, where workers see their hours deducted at times of low demand (or at the discretion of employers) and where unpaid leave is common. These reasons may contribute to Russia’s gender pay gap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>/2017/12/10/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/10/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Thanks for visiting my blog. I’m looking forward to writing some posts about Russia, and learning some much needed R skills here. My rationale for starting, was to learn more about R and blogdown. Since you typically need data for both of those things, I decided to focus on something I’m interested in; Russian Society, labour markets, and sociology. If nothing else, this might be a good exercise for learning blocks of code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>