<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pay on Tupac Lives in Moscow</title>
    <link>/tags/pay/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pay on Tupac Lives in Moscow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/pay/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Compensating Differentials and Premiums for &#34;Dangerous Work&#34;</title>
      <link>/2018/02/04/compensating-differentials-and-premiums-for-dangerous-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/04/compensating-differentials-and-premiums-for-dangerous-work/</guid>
      <description>A key theory predicting differences in pay, and explaining pay inequality, lies in compensating differentials. This is the idea that pay premiums are attached to jobs that have unfavourable or dangerous working conditions. Thus, workers who are at risk earn more than equally skilled workers in safer jobs. The theory often gets cited by critics of the gender pay gap. Here, it is argued that women accept lower pay in trying to “buy” better working conditions (or simply more favourable conditions).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Industry Differences in Pay</title>
      <link>/2017/12/30/gender-parental/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/30/gender-parental/</guid>
      <description>In this post I outline industry differences in pay, with a special focus on gender. I already listed the occupational differences in a previous post. Here, I follow the same idea, but substitute industry for occupations.
As before, I use the Russian Longitudinal Monitoring Survey for data on participants in 2015. I use a measure for gender, industry, the number of weekly hours worked, and gross wages.
I do not limit the industry codes, but focus on industry as it appears in the survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gender, occupations, and pay</title>
      <link>/2017/12/20/gender-occupations-and-pay/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/20/gender-occupations-and-pay/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I look at a small chart breaking down pay by gender and occupation. Russian wages are particularly flexible, employers have significant freedom in setting the earnings of “inefficient” workers. There’s also a lot of “hidden unemployment”, where workers see their hours deducted at times of low demand (or at the discretion of employers) and where unpaid leave is common. These reasons may contribute to Russia’s gender pay gap.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>